Guide to the Henry Draper Image Collection MC.230
New York University Archives
New York University Archives Collection of Late 19th Century Photographic Materials
1862-1926
1862-1898
New York University Archives
Draper, Henry, 1837-1882
Hering, D.W. (Daniel Webster), 1850-1938
Dixon, Antonia
MC.230
x Linear Feet in 40 boxes.
New York University Archives Collection of Late 19th Century Photographic Materials Henry Draper was a physician and dean of faculty of the Medical Department of the University of the City of New York (now New York University). He was also a pioneer in the field of astrophotography. This collection contains many glass plates of his photographs, many of which are astronomical images. Some slides also relate to his research and teaching at the University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Upon Henry Draper's death in 1882 a selection of items in this collection were found in his New York laboratory. Draper's sister, Mrs. Antonia Dixon, presented these items to New York University. The accession number related to this collection is 82.030.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into ten series, arranged in chronological order within.
Series I. Henry Draper Spectra Images Series II. Henry Draper Moon Images Series III. Glass Plate Negative Fragments Series IV. Henry Draper-Related Observatories and Laboratories Images Series V. D.W. Hering X-Ray Images Series VI. NYU Campus, Students, and Related Images Series VII. Lecture Presentation Support Images Series VIII. Daguerreotypes Series IX. Document Reproductions, Memorial Images Series X. Original Storage Housing
Biographical note
Henry Draper was born March 7, 1837, to John William Draper and Antonia Coetana de Paiva Pereira Gardner. John William Draper was a doctor, chemist, and professor at the University of the City of New York (now New York University), and his son Henry followed closely in his footsteps. Henry Draper graduated from the Medical Department of the University of the City of New York in 1857. He became a physician at Bellevue Hospital and later returned to the University as a professor and eventually as dean of faculty of the Medical Department. Despite his employment as a doctor, Draper also spent a large amount of time on his passion of astrophotography. He even built his own observatory on his father's estate at Hastings-on-Hudson. Draper was a pioneer in the astrophotography field, directing an expedition to photograph the 1874 transit of Venus and being the first to photograph an astronomical nebula with his image of the Orion Nebula in 1880. He was also interested in spectra, taking the first image of the stellar spectrum in 1872. Draper also invented the slit spectrograph and improved on many photographic tools such as telescope clock drives which are necessary to steady long photographic exposures.
In 1867 Henry Draper married the wealthy socialite Anna Mary Palmer. Not only was she an able laboratory assistant, but she also helped turn their home into a center for celebrities and scientists. Draper was well recognized, receiving honorary law degrees from the University of the City of New York and the University of Wisconsin, a Congressional medal, and election to both the National Academy of Sciences and the Astronomische Gesellschaft. Unfortunately, Draper became ill during a trip to the Rocky Mountains and died of double pleurisy at the age of 45. His wife established the Henry Draper Memorial that awards the Henry Draper Medal for astrophysics and funded the Henry Draper Catalog, which is a massive photographic stellar spectrum survey.
Source: "Henry Draper," in Biographical Encyclopedia of Astronomers, ed. Thomas Hockey (New York: Springer, 2007).
Custodial History
At some point other items were pulled from an attic at a building on the NYU Heights campus and added to this collection.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Fragile materials will not be handled without the assistance of an archivist. Digital surrogates were created for all images and are available to view through this finding aid. Please contact New York University Archives with any questions regarding digital surrogates.
Related Materials
Draper Family Papers (MC 11)
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of primarily glass plates of images taken by Draper and the wooden cabinet where negatives were stored. They include astrophotography images of the moon and solar spectra along with images of sites of Draper's work, such as the University campus and his observatory at Hastings-on-Hudson. Some of these glass slides have been damaged and now only exist in partial fragments. Additionally, this collection contains Draper's collection of lantern slides of historical images and reproductions of his photographs used in educational presentations.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions, but extremely fragile. It is recommended to use the digital surragates of these images.
Daguerreotype; Lantern slides; Glass plate negatives; Photographic prints.; Astronomical photography; Astronomy.; Dixon, Antonia; New York University -- Faculty -- 19th century
- Series I. Henry Draper Spectra Images, 1873-1882
  - Spectra, August 11, 1870s; cuid1912; Glass plate; Small label is only partially legible: Aug 11th, 187-, 6 PM, 10th. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Spectra, August 12, 1873; cuid1911; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate; Small sticker label: Aug 12, 1873, Midday 5 5. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Spectra -- No. 2, 12 January 1876; cuid1924; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative; possible evidence of mold. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cyanogen, 23 April 1876; cuid1960; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Spectra, 19 June 1876; cuid1919; Narrower than the other plates in collection and appears to be a slightly different photographic process. Wet plate, glass negative; Label: difficult to decipher. The number 4/12 appears between two words or abbreviations. Dated 19 June 76. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Print of Solar Spectrum -- Discovery of Oxygen in the Sun, 1876; cuid2027; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Upper part of photograph is spectrum of sun. Lower part is spectrum of oxygen and nitrogen of air. This is the illustration (probably the original for the reproduction) in the paper about oxygen in the sun (J. Franklin Institute vol. 74).
  - Sun and Air (Leyden Spark) with Coincidence of Oxygen Lines with Bright Lines in the Sun, 1876; cuid2044; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Spectrum of CO2 -- Voighander Between Slit of Plage-Browning Prism Close to Slit, February 1877; cuid1954; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hydrogen 800 Ten Sparks Per Minute ---Browning of Prisms, 14 February 1877; cuid1962; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hydrogen -- 800 Ten Inch Sparks Per Minute -- 10m Ex. -- Browning of Prism, 14 February 1877; cuid1970; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Sun 5S Nitrogen 800 Ten Inch Sparks Per Minute, 17 February 1877; cuid1964; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, 18 February 1877; cuid2074; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Hydrogen 15m Ex. 800 Sparks Per Minute -- No Leyden -- No. 2, 1 March 1877; cuid1967; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hydrogen -- No Leyden -- 15m Ex...No.3, 1 March 1877; cuid1968; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hydrogen -- No Leyden, 3 March 1877; cuid1966; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hydrogen 2nd Ex. of Tube 10m-800 Sparks Red -- No. Leyden, 18 March 1877; cuid1958; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Identification, 24 March 1877; cuid2073; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Leyden, 24 March 1877; cuid1956; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Solar Spectrum with Nitrogen Lab Spectrum for Comparison, 1 April 1877; cuid2067; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with CO2, 3 April 1877; cuid2076; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Air for Comparison, 7 April 1877; cuid2071; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Nitrogen Laboratory Spectrum, 11 April 1877; cuid2064; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison CO2 Identifications, 15 April 1877; cuid2070; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, 15 April 1877; cuid2061; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Laboratory Spectrum, 17 April 1877; cuid2063; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Cyanogen Laboratoy Spectrum, 17 April 1877; cuid2072; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Chloride of Tin -- Nitrogen Only, 18 April 1877; cuid1948; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bromide of Silicon, 18 April 1877; cuid1957; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Fluoride of Silicon Laboratory Spectrum, 23 April 1877; cuid2054; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Bromide of Silicon Laboratory Spectrum, 23 April 1877; cuid2079; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Cyanogen, 23 April 1877; cuid1955; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Carbonic Acid, 28 April 1877; cuid1961; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Carbonic Acid Laboratory Spectrum, 1 May 1877; cuid2066; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Carbonic Acid Laboratory Spectrum, 3 May 1877; cuid2060; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Spectrum of Sulphuret of L--, 21 May 1877; cuid1971; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, 29 May 1877; cuid2078; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Iodine, December 1877; cuid1900; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spectrum of Iodine, December 1877; cuid1905; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Spectrum, 1877; cuid2062; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Sulphur, 1 January 1878; cuid1953; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Sulphur, 1 January 1878; cuid1973; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Spectra, 5 January 1878; cuid1893; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Spectra, 6 January 1878; cuid1888; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sulphuretted Hydrogen, 14 February 1878; cuid1952; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Coal Gas Laboratory Spectrum, 14 February 1878; cuid2057; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Spectra, 15 March 1878; cuid1932; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Spectra, 16 March 1878; cuid1949; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, 16 March 1878; cuid2077; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Spectra, 20 March 1878; cuid1896; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - CO2, April 1878; cuid1925; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, 6 April 1878; cuid2075; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, 6 April 1878; cuid2050; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, 6 April 1878; cuid2051; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, 18 April 1878; cuid2065; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Laboratory Spectrum, 19 April 1878; cuid2059; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Sulphur, 1 June 1878; cuid1885; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Copy of a Corona Taken by A. Clark at Criston, 29 July 1878; cuid2040; Glass plate negative (on emulsion) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, 1878; cuid1950; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Coal Gas Laboratory Spectrum, 1878; cuid2069; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar Corona, 1878; cuid2052; Glass plate (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Solar Spectrum, 6 January 1879; cuid2045; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Spectra -- No. 1, 3 March 1879; cuid1918; Collodion process, wet plate, glass negative (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Spectra -- No. 1, 8 March 1879; cuid1917; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative; possible evidence of mold. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Spectra -- No. 2, 8 March 1879; cuid1913; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate; Has the appearance of mold on the glass plate. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Spectra -- No. 3, 8 March 1879; cuid1916; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Spectra -- No. 2, 10 March 1879; cuid1915; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Spectra, 9 March 1879; cuid1930; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Spectra, 10 March 1879; cuid1926; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, 16 March 1879; cuid1921; Glass plate (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Spectra -- No. 2, 26 March 1879; cuid1907; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Spectra -- No. 3, 26 March 1879; cuid1908; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, 1 April 1879; cuid1929; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Solar Spectrum, 1 April 1879; cuid2046; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Solar Spectrum, 2 April 1879; cuid2047; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Solar Spectrum, 2 April 1879; cuid2042; Glass plate negative (broken) (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, 4 April 1879; cuid1927; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Spectra -- No. 3, 4 April 1879; cuid1906; Wet collodion negative, Glass plate (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Spectra -- No. 1, 6 April 1879; cuid1914; Collodion wet plate, glass negative (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Spectra, 6 April 1879; cuid1928; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bromide of Silicon Laboratory Spectrum, 23 April 1879; cuid2055; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, 11 May 1879; cuid1933; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Solar Spectrum, 15 May 1879; cuid2041; Glass plate negative (broken) (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14876 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14877 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14878 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14879 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14880 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14881 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14882 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14883 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14884 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion 90A / MM-11 Glass Slide, circa 1879; cuid14885 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Carbon Channeled Spectrum, 23 April 1880; cuid1901; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Carbon Bands Identified, 23 April 1880; cuid1903; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Iron Arc Crucible, 23 April 1880; cuid1904; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Crucible and Sun, 25 April 1880; cuid1886; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Carbon Crucible, 25 April 1880; cuid1887; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Carbon Laboratory Spectrum, 25 April 1880; cuid2058; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Carbon and Sun, 1 May 1880; cuid1899; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Carbon In Sun, 1 May 1880; cuid1902; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Granite Spectroscope, 21 May 1880; cuid1895; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Grating -- No. 3, 23 May 1880; cuid1922; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Brating Carbon Crucible, 24 May 1880; cuid1884; Lantern Slide? Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Grating Spectroscope, 24 May 1880; cuid1898; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Grating, 31 May 1880; cuid1894; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Iodine, 17 January 1881; cuid1891; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 1, 18 January 1881; cuid2015; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 2, 18 January 1881; cuid2010; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Maxim, 21 January 1881; cuid1892; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photographic Experiment Ex 60th, 22 January 1881; cuid2011; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment, 23 January 1881; cuid2014; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment, 29 January 1881; cuid2008; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment, 6 February 1881; cuid1993; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 2, 6 February 1881; cuid1984; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Photographic Experiment Grating, 13 February 1881; cuid2009; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Experiment Grating, 13 February 1881; cuid2013; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Sun Prisms, 20 February 1881; cuid2012; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Carbon Ore Prisms, 20 February 1881; cuid1994; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 1, 22 February 1881; cuid1979; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 2, 22 February 1881; cuid1987; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - No. 1 90S, 24 February 1881; cuid1996; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - No. 2 5M Slit 14 / 5000, 24 February 1881; cuid1977; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Carbon Ore 90S, 25 February 1881; cuid1985; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Carbon Ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1986; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - 8648 Carbon Ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1976; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 90S Carbon Ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1978; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Painted on Black, 11 March 1881; cuid1980; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - (?) That I Have and in Stellar (?) Up to Present, 11 March 1881; cuid2025; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Eastman, 11 March 1881; cuid1975; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - New Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2004; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2001; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Lantern No. 2 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2002; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid1998; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid2005; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid2000; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid1999; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman Oxalate, 7 April 1881; cuid1997; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Lantern Pyrogallic Experiments, 7 April 1881; cuid1981; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Old Lantern Oxalate Experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1982; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Old Lantern Oxalate Experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1983; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Photographic Experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1988; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Exposed Oxidate, 7 April 1881; cuid1989; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment, 11 April 1881; cuid2022; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic Experiment, 17 April 1881; cuid1992; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment, 19 April 1881; cuid1990; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Experiment, 23 April 1881; cuid1991; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Focus Photography, 11 March 1882; cuid2018; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 1, 28 May 1882; cuid2020; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic Experiment No. 2, 28 May 1882; cuid2021; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Sun 105 Oxygen, 11 June 1882; cuid2019; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Sun 10S, 11 June 1882; cuid1995; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Carbon, 10 July 1882; cuid2017; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, January, undated; cuid1897; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Spectra, 14 January, undated; cuid1959; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Brass, 25 February, undated; cuid1972; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Spectra, 31 May, undated; cuid1890; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, 12 June, undated; cuid1889; Glass plate (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1909; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1910; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1920; Lantern slide negative. Unsure of photographic process, possibly some kind of wet plate. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1923; Glass plate negative, dry plate. A and B etched above two different figures. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1963; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1931; Glass plate (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1934; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1951; Glass plate (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1943; Glass plate (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1944; Glass slide (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1945; Glass slide (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1946; Glass slide (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid1947; Glass slide (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Puppis -- Spectrum 3923-4505, undated; cuid2016; Cardboard (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Hydrogen -- No Leyden, undated; cuid1965; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Photographic Experiment, undated; cuid2023; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Sun and Air, undated; cuid2024; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid2048; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Enlarged Copy of Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid2043; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison, undated; cuid2068; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar Comparison Spectrum, undated; cuid2049; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Solar Spectrum with Comparison Spectrum, undated; cuid2053; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Coal Gas Laboratory Spectrum, undated; cuid2056; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Canis Minoris D2204, undated; cuid1935; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Leyden, undated; cuid1969; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - D2205, undated; cuid1942; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Photographic Experiment, undated; cuid2003; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Solar? Spectrum D660, undated; cuid2028; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Solar? Spectrum, undated; cuid2031; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2029; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2032; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Objective Prism Plate -- Probably Pleiades, undated; cuid2033; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2034; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Objective Prism Plate -- Star Field, undated; cuid2035; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2036; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Objective Prism Plate, undated; cuid2037; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Objective Prism Plate -- Arcturus, undated; cuid2038; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Copy of Stellar Emission Spectrum No. 23 -- Probably a Reproduction of Draper's Own Plate, undated; cuid2026; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Spectrum No. 24, undated; cuid2030; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - No. 20; D186; 13, undated; cuid1941; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - No. 21; D187; 13, undated; cuid1936; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - No. 22; D204; G; 26, undated; cuid1937; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 17; 0201; 12, undated; cuid1938; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 18; D198; 12, undated; cuid1939; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Portrait of a Woman, undated; cuid2006; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Portraits of a Man, undated; cuid2007; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - No Image, undated; cuid2039; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Untitled, undated; cuid1940; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Series II. Henry Draper Moon Images, 1862, 1872, undated
  - Moon, 17 August 1862; cuid14890; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Moon, 16 August 1862; cuid14891; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - 30 Second Exposure, 24 July 1872; cuid14871 (Box 8, Folder 6)